[
    {
        "question": "What US state is called the `Centennial State`?",
        "answer": "Colorado"
    },
    {
        "question": "What nation is home to the ancient Grand Canal?",
        "answer": "China"
    },
    {
        "question": "What river was connected to Lake Erie by the Erie Canal?",
        "answer": "The Hudson River"
    },
    {
        "question": "Venice`s Grand Canal ends at what huge square, the city`s only piazza?",
        "answer": "Piazza San Marco"
    },
    {
        "question": "What volcano is the world`s tallest mountain, when measured base to summit?",
        "answer": "Mauna Kea"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what modern-day country did the dog called the Rhodesian Ridgeback originate?",
        "answer": "South Africa"
    },
    {
        "question": "What animal can be described as a wild pig from Africa?",
        "answer": "Warthog"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which animal is also known as the wild dog from Australia?",
        "answer": "Dingo"
    },
    {
        "question": "What name is given to 23.5 degrees north latitude?",
        "answer": "Tropic of Cancer"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the submerged fringe of a continent?",
        "answer": "Continental shelf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the seasonal rains that occur in southeast Asia called?",
        "answer": "Monsoons"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country borders Kyrgystan to the east?",
        "answer": "China"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country borders Kyrgystan to the southwest?",
        "answer": "Tajikistan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Chad?",
        "answer": "N`Djamena"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Mongolia?",
        "answer": "Ulaanbaatar, or formerly Ulan Bator"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ulaanbaatar is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Mongolia"
    },
    {
        "question": "The `Buffalo River State Park` is located in which US state?",
        "answer": "Minnesota"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state gets the most rainfall?",
        "answer": "Hawaii"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the rainiest US state?",
        "answer": "Hawaii"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the only continent without native reptiles and snakes?",
        "answer": "Antarctica"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country would you find the world`s lowest elevation airport?",
        "answer": "Bar Yehuda Airfield in Israel"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country`s capital contains another country within its borders?",
        "answer": "Italy (Vatican City, the world`s smallest independent nation-state, is fully contained within the city of Rome, Italy`s capital.)"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Washington, D.C become the capital of the U.S.?",
        "answer": "1800"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US state`s highest peak is Mt. Elbert?",
        "answer": "Colorado`s"
    },
    {
        "question": "What former Soviet Republic lies just across the Gulf of Finland from Finland?",
        "answer": "Estonia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What body of water does the Colorado river empty into?",
        "answer": "The Gulf of California"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city serves as the capital of Northern Ireland?",
        "answer": "Belfast"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city, located on the Mississippi River, is known as `The Gateway to the West`?",
        "answer": "St. Louis"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mt. Everest is located on the border of the Chinese region of Tibet and what other country?",
        "answer": "Nepal"
    },
    {
        "question": "Doha is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Qatar"
    },
    {
        "question": "Doha is the capital of which West Asian country?",
        "answer": "Qatar"
    },
    {
        "question": "The town of Whitby in North Yorkshire is situated at the mouth of what river?",
        "answer": "River Esk"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country is the alcoholic drink Pulque consumed?",
        "answer": "Mexico"
    },
    {
        "question": "Riyadh is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Saudi Arabia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Chablis wine comes from which French wine region?",
        "answer": "Burgundy"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the northernmost outdoor swimming pool?",
        "answer": "Troms\u00f8, Norway -- Known as the `Gateway to the Arctic Circle,` it is located so far north that temperatures rarely exceed 60 degrees even in summer."
    },
    {
        "question": "What nation is the largest importer of pork?",
        "answer": "China -- Pork is the most widely consumed meat in the world. China imported $5.93 billion in pork in 2019, more than $1 billion more than second place on the list of top importers."
    },
    {
        "question": "In Ireland, what is known as `the Black Stuff`?",
        "answer": "Guinness -- Even though Ireland`s famous potent potable is often referred to as `the Black Stuff`, Guinness is actually a deep ruby red color."
    },
    {
        "question": "In 2014, a criminal gang in China used the chemical rongalite to flood the market with which contaminated food?",
        "answer": "Tofu"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is Earth`s smallest ocean?",
        "answer": "Arctic Ocean"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Bhutan?",
        "answer": "Thimphu"
    },
    {
        "question": "Harare is the capital of what country?",
        "answer": "Zimbabwe"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Zimbabwe?",
        "answer": "Harare"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Azerbaijan?",
        "answer": "Baku"
    },
    {
        "question": "Baku is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Azerbaijan"
    },
    {
        "question": "`Oro y Plata` (Gold and Silver) is the motto for which U.S. state?",
        "answer": "Montana"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the Japanese term `Sandai Wagyu` translate as?",
        "answer": "Three Big Beefs (Sandai Wagyu are `the three big beefs` - Matsusaka, \u014cmi and the most-famous of all, Kobe.)"
    },
    {
        "question": "A tandoor is a type of what?",
        "answer": "Oven"
    },
    {
        "question": "For the film `The Empire Strikes Back,` where were scenes set on the ice planet Hoth actually filmed?",
        "answer": "The Battle of Hoth scenes were shot on Handangerjokulen Glacier near the village of Finse, Norway."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which U.S state`s motto is `Industry`?",
        "answer": "Utah"
    }
]